const BankingPart2 = [
	{
		questionText: 'what is Fixed Interest Loan',
		ans: ['This interest rate will not be changed throughout the loan tenure', 'They are mostly short Termed'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Factors of Floating Interest Loan',
		ans: [' (External Benchmark) + spread + risk premium.', 'But benchmark is regularly updated So, resultant interest rate may increase or decrease throughout the tenure of loan.'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Teaser Loan?',
		ans: ['A sub-type of Floating interest rate loan, wherein initial years have low interest, but afterwards- higher interest rate.', 'While RBI has not banned Teaser loans but has put stricter regulations on them from 2011.'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'TYPES OF LOANS: BASED ON INTEREST RATE',
		ans: ['Fiexed, Floating, Teaser'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'TYPES OF LOANS: BASED ON BORROWERS',
		ans: ['Prime Borrower', 'Subprime Brrower-Individual', 'OverLeveraged Borrower-company', 'Zombie Lending'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Zombie Lending',
		ans: ['When a weak bank keeps giving new loans to a subprime / overleveraged borrower.'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'What is Twin Balance Syndrome',
		ans: ['It is situation in economy when company profits decreases and banks hesistates to give loans as NPA may increase', 'It happens after 2008 subprime crises'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'What is Interest Coverage Ratio',
		ans: ['It shows can company covers the interest'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'What is NPA',
		ans: ['If loan principal or interest is not paid for more than 90 days from its due date, then such loan account is classified as Non-Performing Asset (NPA).', 'For farm loans, NPA is not counted on number of days but on number of cropping seasons. '],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'What is standard Assets?',
		ans: ['Loan account where borrower is repaying the principal and interest in timely manner'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'What is the proccess to declare a Loan Account as NPA',
		ans: ['SMA-0:- If loan principal or interest unpaid for 1-30 days from its due date, then such loan account is classified as Special Mention Account-0.', 'SMA-1:- 31-60 day', 'SMA-2 61-90 days'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'What is the provisions for NPA',
		ans: ['As per RBI norms, banks must set aside funds to cover losses against their NPA', 'Such ‘provisioning of funds’ ⏬decrease profitability of the Bank. '],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'what is Gross NPA',
		ans: ['Gross non-performing assets = grand total of all NPA loans'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'What is NET NPA',
		ans: ['NET NPA = GNPA Minus Provisioning'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'What is Substandard Assests',
		ans: ['When loan account remains in the NPA classification for 12 months or more/>'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Doubtful Asset',
		ans: ['When loan account in substandard classification for 12 months or more />'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Loss Asset',
		ans: ['When a bank, its auditor or RBI declares that given doubtful asset has little / no salvageable value. (नीलामी करके भी नुकसान भरपाई असं भव)'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Loan write-off',
		ans: ['banker removes a loan amount from the ‘asset-side’ of the bank balance sheet, to save corporation tax', 'Loan write-off doesn’t waive bank’s right to recover that bad loan, it’s merely an accounting exercise for tax-benefits.'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Effect Loan write off on NPAs? ',
		ans: ['Loan write-off⏬ reduces the NPA% of the Bank (Because amount is written-off/cancelled from balance sheet)', 'NEWS: 2022-Dec: Government replied in Parliament that Banks write off loans worth Rs 11.17 lakh crore in last six years'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Restructured Loan',
		ans: ['When principal / interest rate / tenure of the loan is modified. Banks may do it when borrower facing difficulty in repaying loans.'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Stressed Asset',
		ans: ['NPA + Loans Written-Off + Restructured Loans = Stressed Assets'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'One Time Settlement with Haircut',
		ans: ['For example, If bank allows the borrower to pay 60% of dues & forgoes 40% as loss, then bank has offered “One time Settlement (OTS) with 40% haircut'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Evergreening of loans',
		ans: ['When a borrower taking a new loan to pay off his old loan.'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'KV Kamath Report is related to?',
		ans: ['2020: RBI had setup this Committee to look into loan restructuring for large companies, who are hit by Corona pandemic'],

	},
	{
		questionText: 'SARFAESI ACT 2002 was based on which company report?',
		ans: ['1998: Narsimhan-II'],
	},
	{
		questionText: ' RBI setup ___________ Committee to suggest reforms for ARCs',
		ans: ['Sudarshan Sen Comittee'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'what are powers under SARFAESI act',
		ans: ['Lenders can attach the mortgaged assets when loan is not repaid.', 'change board of directors in such companies', ', can also sell such assets to Asset Reconstruction Companies (ARC, NBFC)', 'SARFAESI not applicable on farm loans'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Legal Rights of Defaulter against SARFAESI Act?',
		ans: ['Debt Recovery  Tribunal --> Debt Recovery Appealent Tribunal(50% disputed amount as security deposit)---> High Court'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'SARFAESI act full form',
		ans: ['Securitization and Reconstruction of Financial Assets and Enforcement of Security Interest '],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Which NBFCs are eligible to use SARFAESI powers',
		ans: ['The NBFC having asset size of ₹100 cr or more, AND  loan given is at least ₹20 lakhs.', 'All Housing Finance Companies (HFCs) have powers'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'When was IBC code came into force?',
		ans: ['2016'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'NCLT must accept/reject application within ____ days to initiate proceedings under the I&B Code.  ',
		ans: ['14'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'What is Pre-packaged Insolvency Resolution Process (PIRP)',
		ans: ['Unofficial way to deal IBC code', 'only for MSME', 'Time Limit:120days'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Time limit Corporate Insolvency Resolution Process (CIRP) ',
		ans: ['330 days'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'what is IBC Ordinance / Act 2020 ?',
		ans: ['Min default loan to register case in IBC changed from 1 L to 1Cr'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Current chairman of IBBI(Insolvency and Bankruptcy Board of India)',
		ans: ['Ravi Mittal (2022)'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'IBBI comes under which Ministry?',
		ans: ['Ministry of Corporate Affairs'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Who selects Insolvency Professionals Agencies (IPAs)',
		ans: ['IBBI  from 1) ICAI (Chartered Accounts) 2) ICSI (Company Secretaries) and 3) Institute of Cost Accountants. '],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'What is Information Utility (IU) in IBBI',
		ans: ['IU is a database of borrowers', 'It is compulsory for lenders to share data with IU.'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'what is \'Injeti Srinivas\' commitee about',
		ans: ['IB'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'what is Centre for Processing Accelerated Corporate Exit (C-PACE',
		ans: ['Provision for Voluntary Liquidation of companies (CRILC)” for Loans above Rs 5 cr', 'Banks & NBFCs have to submit weekly updates in this portal.'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'What is CRILC',
		ans: ['RBI has setup “Central Repository of Information on Large Credits '],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Which commitee propose Public Credit Registry(PCR) ',
		ans: ['RBI’s Yeshwant M. Deosthalee Committee'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Legal Entity Identifier (LEI) Number',
		ans: ['RBI has ordered all companies undertaking crossborder transactions of Rs 50 crore or more to quote this number in financial transaction.'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'What is DICGC',
		ans: ['Deposit Insurance and Credit Guarantee Corporation'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Bad Banks consits of?',
		ans: ['NARCL-ARC -National Asset Reconstruction Company Ltd', 'IDRCL-AMC: India Debt Resolution Company Ltd'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'what is Promt Corrective Action (PCA) Framework',
		ans: ['Under PCA framework, RBI classifies the scheduled commercial banks (SCB) into Risk threshold #1,#2, #3 based on its capital, loan-asset quality etc. Higher the number, higher the risk'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Daksh web system is realated to?',
		ans: ['Web system wherein Banks, NBFC send their compliance reports to RBI'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Who is Lending/loan service provider?',
		ans: ['A lending/Loan Service Provider (LSP) is financial technology (Fintech) company that connects borrowers with lender (Banks & NBFCs). e.g. Lazypay, Bank Bazaar, Paisa Bazaar'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'What is FIRST LOSS DEFAULT GUARANTEE (FLDG) norm by RBI   ',
		ans: ['Digital lender have to pay some portion of loss to the bank if customer defaults'],
	},
	// {
	// 	questionText: '',
	// 	ans: [''],
	// },
];

export default BankingPart2;
